Gus Shaal

Phone: +353 899 788 046 | Email: ghiathchaal.beg@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/gus-shaal/

Location: Tallaght, Dublin 24 | GitHub: github.com/GusTheProgrammer

ABOUT ME

I am currently a final year Computer Science and Information Technology student at Technological University Dublin Tallaght. I'm currently an intern at Fidelity Investments where I've gained hands-on experience as a Software Engineer. I am looking forward to transitioning into a full-time software development role where I can further refine the full stack development skills that I have obtained in my academic journey and recent work experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient in Python, Java, JavaScript, and familiar with web development frameworks like Spring Boot and Django.
- Strong foundation in Object-Oriented Software development, Agile methodologies, and RESTful web application creation.
- Experience with various database technologies including Redis and implementing real-time communication with WebSockets.
- Capable of deploying web applications using cloud services, managing repositories with version control systems, and creating CI/CD pipelines.
- Knowledge of containerization technologies, virtual machines, Linux, and creating visually appealing front-end interfaces.
- Understanding of AtScale platform and semantic layer concepts.
- Excellent analytical and troubleshooting skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

JAN 2023 - AUG 2023

Fidelity Investments | Dublin, Ireland

- Created a tool for automating onboarding metadata on Collibra using Spring Boot, following agile practices and undergoing code and design reviews.
- Created a Python script to collect telemetry data from the AtScale tool, providing data for visualization and analysis.
- Gained proficiency in understanding the AtScale platform, semantic layer concepts, and data lakes like Snowflake.
- Migrated the team's Confluence documentation space to a new space with a 3rd-party plugin, enhancing visual representation and readability.
- Worked on a project with a group of interns to redesign a local charity's website using React, adhering to modern design guidelines to
 increase the charity's brand visibility.
- Collaborated with teams in the US and India.

Research Volunteer MAY 2021 - SEP 2021

CSinc – TUD Tallaght | Dublin, Ireland

- Examined learning materials and sought ways to improve them.
- Researched new methods of delivering highly technical content.
- Rewrote Python exercises and materials.
- Created scripts to increase the interactivity of the material.
- Improved the visual appeal of the material.

Volunteer SEP 2017 - MAY 2018

Marino Credit Union | Dublin, Ireland

- Scanned and organized documents.
- Assisted members in updating their info.
- Created scripts to automate data input.
- Calculated the end-of-day reconciliation sheet.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computing with Software Development (3.8 GPA)

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Technological University Dublin Tallaght Campus

Academic Project:

Developed a real-time chat application capable of handling group chats, private chats, and real-time notifications using Django, JavaScript, WebSockets, Postgres SQL, Redis, HTML5, and Bootstrap 5.

INTERESTS

Tabletop Games | Travelling | Working out

REFERENCES

Available on request.